Rolf Britten

Curriculum Vitae

Tel: (+44) 1234 123456 Address Line 1, Address Line 2

E-mail: rolfbritten@gmail.com Address Postcode

Near-qualified Actuary with a proven record of leading and delivering high-quality analyses and projects. Experienced in Motor Risk Pricing with a particular interest in nascent pricing technologies and techniques.

Professional Experience

AXA Insurance:

Technical Pricing Manager March 2019 - Present

- Responsible for maintenance and improvement of AXA Direct Motor's risk pricing layer.
- Leading projects, analysis and providing line management responsibilities across a team of 4 analysts.
- Delivered first incremental refresh of machine learning (ML) risk models. Using innovative new features, collaborating with Data Science.
- Peril Allocation research project found more predictive splits for Injury claims.
- Work in progress to re-build AvsE interactive reporting. Automatically flag and rank interactive segments.

Senior Technical Pricing Analyst January 2018 - February 2019

- Involved throughout the delivery of new ML model suite. Main overseer of raw modelling data wrangling, eRate build, Impact Analysis and project retrospective.
- Drove forward Motor Technical Pricing activities including ML project, investigations into emerging pricing issues and securing committee buy-in for trial ramp up and tweaks.
- Supported members of the team with technical problems and shared areas of knowledge I have gained from a large spectrum of pricing work.
- Feature engineering from test-level MOT data, followed by analysis and presentation of statistically significant pricing deficiencies.
- Developed a number of bespoke functions for in-house R package including creation of PDP function and dynamic html MI packs which were instrumental in explaining ML results to stakeholders.
- Chairing regular meeting for cross-team analysts to present work and share knowledge.
- End of year review rating of 'Excellent'.

Technical Pricing Analyst June 2015 - December 2017

- Refresh of Motor Insurance EMBlem Risk Pricing models suite from SAS Data Prep to post-deploy analysis and monitoring.
- Developed in-house alternative to market-leading geographic analysis tool in R. Incorporated several bespoke algorithms to compete/ensemble. Tool has been shared across business units, including overseas, with consistent improvement in performance on unseen data.
- Examined claims development across rating factors and created bootstrap solution to assess significance of observed differences.
- Wrote updated Motor Expected Loss Ratio (ELR) process. Integrated stochastic elements to produce confidence intervals on reported ELR to demonstrate to stakeholders variance of loss ratio predictions, especially over smaller business volumes.
- End of year review ratings of 'Excellent' and 'Outstanding'.

eRate (Rating Engine) Analyst April 2014 - June 2015

- Received award from MD for delivering Group Internal Audit action to set up automated solution for testing of aggregator mappings against a tight deadline. This involved designing a solution from scratch and the delegation of work to peers.
- Devised several highly effective changes to eRate processes including digestible log of production rating models for stakeholders and Weekly Deploy Stand Up.
- Proactively working with several areas of the business (such as pricing, projects and IT teams) in order to deliver accurate and timely pricing changes, small change, defect fixes and projects.
- End of year review rating of 'Excellent'.

Buckinghamshire County Council - Legal & Democratic Services:

Assistant Complaints Officer/Assistant Claims Handler: Jun – Aug 2012; Jul 2013 – Mar 2014

• Processing and investigating public liability claims against the council. Repudiating claims or requesting settlement from contractors, based on evidence of due diligence/negligence.

Education

2016 -	Institute and Faculty of Actuaries Near-qualified
	CT1-9 - 77% average, CA1, SP7, SP8, SA3
2010 - 2013	University of Exeter BSc [Hons] Mathematics - 2:1
	Advanced Statistical Modelling, Stochastic Processes, Numerics and Optimisation
2008 - 2010	Aylesbury Grammar School A Level - AAB

Skills

Technical Knowledge I am motivated by the challenge of designing elegant solutions to business problems.

I have a high level of proficiency in **R** and **SAS**, experienced in **VBA**, **SQL** and **Git**, amongst others.

I continuously look to add to my technical skill set, whether that be Actuarial Exams, research projects at work or coding courses in my own time, e.g. Data Camp (**Pvthon**), Coursera (**Java**)

Leadership and Communication I enjoy working closely with my team, mentoring them and other junior colleagues - helping them to understand and work on complex issues is very rewarding.

I have taken many of pieces of work to various committees for approval or discussion. I have often received positive feedback on my **presentation and communication** from attendees within and outside of pricing. I ran my own regular meeting, curating the agenda and modifying the format to give the most value to the analyst community.

My early career at AXA put me at the heart of many IT projects, introducing me to the benefits of **Agile project methodologies**. I adopt these into my management of large projects as well as analyst work stack.

Innovation Where appropriate I will look to complete projects and ad-hoc work in a way that challenges and improves processes, without sacrifices to objective outcomes.

Throughout my career at AXA I have made improvements to many processes across the eRate and Pricing team. For example writing and sharing R functions and SAS macros to cut analyst time spent on repetitive work and rewriting code. Results have improved run times, readability and accuracy.

I encourage my team to develop and share R tools and processes that improve our ways of working and communication of our results to stakeholders.

Interests

Keen **long-distance road cyclist**. Role as lead cyclist in AXA charity cycle rides - in charge of the safety, coherence and team work of groups on the road.

Charity volunteer - assisting in the running of STAR's (Student Action for Refugees) annual conferences and training events. I also provide technical consultancy and have produced promotional videos.